Finding Aid for St. John’s Episcopal Church, Temperance, Mich. records, 1963-1997
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
St. John’s Episcopal Church, Temperance, Mich. records 1963-1997
St. John’s Episcopal Church (Temperance, Mich.)
1.5 linear feet and 3 oversize volumes
0242 Ba 2
St. John’s Episcopal Church was established in 1963 in Temperance, MI. The church closed in 1997 due to dwindling membership. The records contain meeting minutes, photographs, financial reports, correspondence, and membership and church activity records.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group came from the Episcopal Church, Diocese of Michigan (donor no. 1059.
The record group is open to research.
St. John's Episcopal Church, established in 1963, served the area around Temperance, MI. The Episcopal Diocese of Michigan along with Reverend C. M. Stuart and the Trinity Episcopal Church parish in Monroe, MI, founded St. John's Mission. Bishop Archie H. Crowley held the first service on July 21, 1963, at the Temperance Library. Land was purchased in November 1964, and on July 25, 1969, the Mission held a groundbreaking ceremony. It was not until January 18, 1970, when the first service was held at the new church building. During its history, the church conducted traditional services and ceremonies sanctioned by the Episcopalian faith. In 1997, the Church closed down because of the dwindling numbers of active members.
St. John's Episcopal Church records consist of The records contain meeting minutes, photographs, financial reports, correspondence, and membership and church activity records. The records are organized into eight series: Registers of baptisms, communicants, burials, marriages, etc.; Registers of services; Membership records; Photographs and Background Material; Activities; Administrative Records; Bishop's Committee Meetings, and Miscellaneous.
Subjects:
St. John's Episcopal Church (Temperance, Mich.); Registers of births, etc.--Michigan--Temperance.; Episcopal Church--Michigan--Temperance.; Temperance (Mich.)--Church history.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Registers of baptisms, communicants, burials, marriages, etc.
  - 1963-1982, 1 volume (Box 1)
  - 1981-1996 (Volume 1)
  - Baptisms (loose materials), 1979-1996 (Box 1)
  - Confirmations (loose materials), 1965, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Marriages (loose materials), 1980-1985 (Box 1)
- Registers of Services
  - 1963-1977 (Box 1)
  - 1977-1997 (Box 1)
- Membership records
  - Transfers, 1965-1996 (Box 1)
  - St. John's Parish list, 1963-1968 (Volume 2)
- Photographs and Background Material
  - Scrapbook / photograph album of church activities and personalities, 1963-1970 (Volume 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 2)
  - Historical Background, 1963-1997 (Box 2)
- Activities
  - Fall Retreat, undated (Box 2)
  - Memorial Committee, 1984 (Box 2)
  - Youth Ministry, circa 1960s and 1984 (Box 2)
- Administrative Records
  - Building Donations, 1969-1973 (Box 2)
  - Financial Reports, 6 folders
    - 1970-1975, 5 folders (Box 2)
    - 1996-1997 (Box 2)
  - Grant Proposals, 1981-1986, 1994 (Box 2)
  - Loan Repayment, 1982-1983 (Box 2)
  - Salary and Benefit Policy Committee, 1972-1976 (Box 2)
- Bishop's Committee Meeting
  - Meeting minutes
    - 1963-1975, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1980-1982, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - 1987-1994, 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Secretary's records (?) containing minutes and financial material (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous
  - Lay Readers, 1983, 1998 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous programs, newspapers, announcements, 1967-1971 (Box 2)